♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
‪["Mr. Tailor" playing]
‪-‪♪ Fix this‪ ♪
‪-‪♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor‪ ♪
‪♪ ‪Holding the scissors‪ ♪
‪♪ ‪One cut, and it's settled‪ ♪
[Tonet] I just want to correct
what Atoy knows!
You're toying with them!
[Mongki] At last,
I can get back at you now!
PREVIOUSLY
- [thumps, then thuds]
- [groans]
- [whistle blowing]
- [guard] Stop!
[clamoring]
[Martina, in English]
It's better if you die.
[in English] I wish I could say
I'm sorry, but I'm not!
[Martina gasps]
[Ibyang] Tatoy, it's moving… Sister Tonet?
I have to say--
Tonet, don't speak. I'll call for help.
Janine, she's not--
She's not…
[Ibyang] Sister Tonet, wake up!
Wake up! [wails]
[woman] Someone had
an accident. She might be dead!
Atoy!
Bro, Tonet had an accident.
[Atoy] She's the one
we put in the ambulance.
- [ambulance siren wailing]
- Stop that!
My sister's inside!
Stop, stop!
[Emerson] Netchai, Netchai.
[Cita sobbing] Tonet didn't make it.
Emerson, she's gone.
[shouting] She can't die!
She can't die, Miss Cita!
She can't be dead!
I was just with my sister!
- Emerson. She's gone.
- She was just there!
[sobbing and wailing]
Emerson…
It's confirmed. Tonet is dead.
You can breathe now.
Don't worry, okay?
- [Cita] Let's go to her.
- I'll see you at home…
- Hey.
- [gasps]
Why are you hitting people? Are you blind?
You're the one who hit me.
[suspicious music playing]
You look familiar.
I know you.
Red Regalia?
Ah…
You're the one
who threatened Atoy with a gun!
[scoffs]
It's useless anyway.
[sinister music playing]
What? Are you going to punch me?
Are you only tough against old women?
Huh?
Mom.
Try it.
Brother Atoy is going to finish you.
[music concludes]
[suave theme music playing]
Sis Ame, will Sis Tonet survive?
I'm worried.
When I held her,
she closed her eyes and never woke up!
Maybe…
Tonet was just tired at that time.
But she's in the hospital now.
They won't neglect her there.
Maybe we can visit her tomorrow.
[somber music playing]
- [Audrey] Hi.
- [Janine, in English] Mommy!
My child.
Atoy mentioned what happened.
How is Tonet?
[phone ringing]
I'll find out in a moment.
Hello, Miss Cita?
How is Tonet?
Is she okay?
All right.
Yes, Miss Cita. I'll take care of it.
Thank you.
Sis Ame, what did Miss Cita say?
Can we visit Sis Tonet?
Ibyang, don't think about that for now.
Just think…
that Sister Tonet is happy
because you didn't leave her alone.
And also, she really loves you.
Mm?
But Sis Ame, I already know that.
And you're not answering my question.
Ibyang…
The doctors struggled
to treat Tonet's wounds.
Her body couldn't take it anymore.
We will never be with her again.
She's gone.
[melancholic music playing]
[insudible]
[sobbing]
So… Sister Tonet is dead?
[sobs]
My Sister Tonet!
[wailing]
Sister Tonet…
[in English] I'm so sorry, Ibyang.
Mommy, I want to go home.
[in English] Please?
[Ibyang] Sister Tonet…
[in English] Tonet, I'm sorry.
If only I knew last night
was the last time we'd talk…
[sobbing]
Feeling giddy but with a question mark?
Is she trying to be trendy?
Are you really in love or not?
Or are you just leading him on?
Hey!
Girl, just ignore it.
You know what? Let's just eat siomai.
You go ahead. I don't feel like it.
[gentle music playing]
Ah, tomorrow.
Come with me. I'll deliver
a suit to a client.
Then after that, let's get a foot spa.
[in English] Girly time!
I still have to help
at the blood donation drive tomorrow.
You go ahead.
After that? It's only half day, right?
You still don't want to?
[music fades]
- You!
- Give me that!
[gentle music playing]
Remember this.
[in English] You need to enjoy
and live your life to the fullest!
Even if you know Gavin doesn't like you
and Cathy is the one he really wants.
Oh, be careful.
You might miss doing the things you want,
because you're always looking
for reasons to be mad at Cathy.
There are things that
will never go your way.
Oh, whatever, Karla!
I'll just leave. I'll eat siomai instead.
[in English] "To sio-mai love for you."
[laughs]
Ha.
You really don't want to?
[music fades]
[sobbing]
I should have gone with you.
I should have bonded with you.
- [sobbing continues]
- [melancholic music playing]
And I didn't grant your request.
[in English] I'm sorry, Tonet.
[melodramatic music playing]
[in English] I'm so sorry.
[sobbing]
[music fades]
Janine… My child, I'm so sorry.
I didn't know…
you were close to Tonet.
Um, no. I wasn't close to her.
I just feel guilty.
Mm, Janine!
Are you with Atoy?
[Janine] No.
Then who are you with?
None of your business.
Janine!
I saw her in the mall restroom.
She was looking for Daddy.
But I didn't say we were together.
- [heavy breathing]
- [pensive music playing]
I ran away because I didn't
want to be with her.
She was on Ibyang's side.
[music fades]
Dear, I'm sorry.
[somber music playing]
Why are you like that, Janine?
You should have brought Tonet to Tatoy.
Maybe nothing bad would've happened!
Maybe she wouldn't have had the accident.
Maybe she'd still be alive!
Ibyang… Oh, my dear…
Don't blame Janine.
I didn't know that would happen!
Don't pick a fight with me!
I'll fight you…
because you're really bad!
[sobs]
[Audrey] Ibyang. Ibyang, listen to me.
- [sobbing]
- I know this is painful you.
But Janine didn't want
for Tonet to die.
No, but she's really bad!
[sobbing]
Because of you…
I lost someone…
who loved me!
[sobbing]
Because of you!
You always want to be the star!
[sobbing]
What more do you want, Janine? [sobbing]
You have a mother. You have a father!
Isn't that enough for you? [sobs]
You're so selfish!
[sobbing]
[melodramatic music playing]
Rest now, Netchai.
[somber music playing]
Thank you for showing yourself to me.
You still made me feel your love.
- [melancholic music playing]
- [clicks tongue]
[sighs]
- [Atoy] What's the news, 'Son?
- [Cita sobs]
What did the police and the admin say?
- I spoke to them, but…
- [Cita sobs]
[sniffles, clicks tongue]
I couldn't understand
what they said about Tonet's death.
- A "freak accident"?
- [Cita sobs]
She… She was just hit
by some scaffolding, like that?
[Cita] Well, according to a witness,
there was a man forcing her
to go with him because…
he accused her of stealing something.
[stammers]
So Tonet ran, because she denied it.
She never did that.
He tried to drag her to the precinct.
Maybe security chased her,
and that's how she ended up
in that vacant area under construction.
- Impossible. That's impossible.
- [Cita sniffles]
- My sister would never steal.
- [Cita inhales]
Who was the man accusing her of theft?
[rousing music playing]
[mysterious music playing]
Martina.
The maid told me you've been
drinking since you got here.
What's your problem?
Tonet is dead.
[in English] I just need to unwind
and get outside of my mind.
[in English] Jeez.
That's your second bottle!
Wasn't that enough to unwind?
[in English] I know what you're saying.
But I can't get her face
out of my mind. Okay?
It's the first time I killed someone.
[in English] I've never done that!
[in English] I feel sick to my stomach
just thinking about it.
[sighs]
[in English] Just let me freaking drink.
[in English] Okay.
If that calms you down,
go ahead, get drunk.
[music intensifies]
But you killed her for a good reason.
If Tonet were alive, we'd be ruined.
[in English] So, relax.
[in English] I'm proud of you.
[in English] Okay?
[in English] Wanna sip?
[music fades]
[Mercado] I emailed
the CV of SPO3 Miguel Reyes.
What's this for, Padua?
Just a personal mission, sir.
My assistant at the shop, Tonet…
She died, sir.
I suspect
it wasn't an accident.
This SPO3 Miguel Reyes…
I researched. He's the officer
assigned to this case.
Ah.
So, you're going to be a cop now?
You'll need an ID and a badge.
I can't produce those.
I don't need a real ID and badge, Colonel.
[rock music playing]
[Mercado chuckles softly]
Looks like you're prepared.
[in English] Good luck, Padua.
[Atoy, in English] Thank you, sir.
[music swells]
[device blipping]
Wait a moment, okay.
I'll just go to the restroom.
[phone ringing]
[line ringing]
[voice recording, in English]
I'm sorry, all circuits are--
[T-Bak] Hey, Karla!
Karla.
We heard what happened to Tonet.
Yes, she's gone.
She had an accident.
[in English] I'm so sorry, Karla.
Let me hug you too.
Thank you for being here.
Even if I didn't call you,
you're here for me.
Of course.
We're your best friends, right?
We won't leave you.
We'll be with you through everything.
And Karla, this is for life.
Come on.
We're your backup
and support in everything.
That's correct!
[in English] Does… Does Gavin know?
[in English] He's with Cathy.
[in English] I'll call him right now.
Ah, no, don't.
I don't want you to disturb
their date with my bad news.
Just let him be.
[somber music playing]
[music fades]
Uh, Officer Reyes, good evening.
- What do you need?
- [in English] Good evening.
I'm investigating what happened
to, um… Tonet, Tonet Mendoza.
I gathered that
she was accused of stealing
before she died.
What item was she supposed to have stolen?
Sir, nothing specific was mentioned.
But there were two victims.
One woman said it was a cell phone.
Cell phone?
[suspicious music playing]
But no cell phone was found
among her things,
except her own.
Maybe she threw it away
while she was running.
You know how thieves are
when they're about to be caught.
It's strange, because Tonet
had no police record.
So, it looks like
she really wasn't a thief.
It also said she worked
at a tailoring shop in Baclaran.
So, she had a job. She seemed decent.
And she wasn't part of any gang.
She wasn't on the gang list.
So…
When I spoke to her brother,
he said she went to the mall to meet him.
So, what did the man and woman
who accused her look like?
Sir, the man was tall, fair-skinned.
The way he dressed, he looked rich!
And the woman was beautiful, round eyes.
I can't forget what Tonet said,
that they seemed like accomplices.
She said they were husband and wife.
A husband and wife, you say?
[tense music playing]
This CCTV of yours?
Can I see it?
Sir, our computer system crashed
during the fire alarm.
All the recorded files
from that day were erased.
So, we don't have any footage.
- Erased?
- [in English] Yes, sir.
How could it be erased?
[music intensifies]
Unless someone erased it.
[music swells]
[suspicious music playing]
Expensive perfume.
[music fades]
This isn't the perfume Tonet wore.
[tense music playing]
[music fades]
[Audrey groans]
[in English] Say that again, Audrey.
Janine saw Tonet… die?
[in English] I'm not sure.
But she saw Tonet's condition
when she had the accident inside the mall.
What she said…
she was covered in blood.
[in English] Oh, uh, that must be
traumatizing for her.
Uh, but why did Atoy
even bring the child there?
He didn't mean to, Dad.
[in English] It's just…
It's just all so sudden.
This morning, Tonet was here
to see me, and now…
she's gone.
[in English] Well, I mean,
that's life, right, Audrey?
We never really know when we'll be taken.
And, Audrey, please
don't let Janine sleep
at her father's house.
[in English] It doesn't seem
like she's safe with him.
You don't know Atoy.
Wow! Now you're defending him?
[suspicious music playing]
[in English] Wait. Uh, Martina…
Have you been drinking?
[in English] Yes. Sorry, Dad. Just, uh…
[in English] Um, trying
to wind down a little bit.
Uh, I'm a little bit tipsy.
I'm not used to it anymore.
[in English] So, I think I'm just gonna…
[Dmitri, in English]
Wait. What happened to your bag?
[in English] It's missing a stud. Look.
There, see?
[in English] Oh.
I just noticed it now.
- Where did you go the whole day?
- [Martina mutters]
- [suspicious music playing]
- [dramatic stinging]
- [dramatic sting]
- [tense music playing]
‪[electronic blipping]
Ah, sorry…
I just got distracted by your bag.
[in English] Oh, thank you!
[in English] It's my favorite one!
My lucky bag.
But it seems… something's missing,
a little broken.
Like it's missing a stud. Just like… this?
UP NEXT
There's evidence. We need to divert it.
Find out if Emerson
will file a case against his wife.
If Emerson pushes through
with his complaint,
what will happen to him?
Maybe Emerson will be next.
He'll end up like his sister.
The mother of your child…
She's part of the Regalia family.
If things get tough,
whose side will you take?
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias